jmbullion.com 2017-11-28

# Privacy Policy and Customer Security - JM Bullion

**Effective Date: November 21, 2016  
**

JMBullion.com; its related services and products (“Website”); and JM Bullion App (“App”) are owned and operated by JM Bullion, Inc. (“JM Bullion” “our,” “we” or “us”).  JM Bullion is deeply committed to respecting and protecting the privacy and security rights of users and the information you share with us at the JM Bullion Website. JM Bullion created this Privacy Policy to provide you with assurance of JM Bullion’s commitment to fair information practices and to the protection of your privacy as you visit and use the Website. This Privacy Policy explains what we do with your information and what you can expect from us. By using the Website, you indicate your acceptance of this Privacy Policy.

JM Bullion’s data collection and retention practices are designed to provide transparency, accountability and choice regarding the management and use of your personal information. If you have questions or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy or practices, please contact us via e-mail at support@jmbullion.com. You may also obtain support by calling 800-276-6508.

This Privacy Policy is only applicable to this Website and not to any Websites of third parties, which may have data collection, storage and use practices and policies that differ from this Privacy Policy. You should consult privacy policies for all other sites, as we have no control over information submitted to or collected by such third parties.

JM BULLION MAY CHANGE, MODIFY, AMEND, SUSPEND, TERMINATE, OR REPLACE THIS PRIVACY POLICY FROM TIME TO TIME AND WITHIN ITS SOLE AND ABSOLUTE DISCRETION. IN THE EVENT JM BULLION CHANGES, MODIFIES, AMENDS, OR REPLACES THIS PRIVACY POLICY, THE EFFECTIVE DATE, LOCATED ABOVE, WILL CHANGE.  YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THE WEBSITE AFTER A CHANGE IN THE EFFECTIVE DATE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY CONSTITUTES YOUR MANIFESTATION OF ASSENT TO THE CHANGE, MODIFICATION, AMENDMENT, OR REPLACEMENT CONTAINED WITHIN.

**BY USING THE WEBSITE, YOU REPRESENT AND WARRANT THAT YOU HAVE READ AND UNDERSTAND, AND AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY.   IF YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND OR DO NOT AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU MUST IMMEDIATELY LEAVE THE WEBSITE.**

  1. **PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

JM Bullion collects some information that is personal (i.e., information that identifies an individual either alone or in combination with other data). JM Bullion also collects non-personal information that does not, on its own, identify an individual person. When non-personal information is combined with other information so that it does identify an individual person, we treat that combination as personally identifiable information.

JM Bullion collects personal information when you provide it to us. The following are examples of the types of personal information that may be collected, directly from you:

  * Name
  * City, state and zip code
  * Email address
  * Date of birth
  * Telephone number
  * Company name
  * Payment information, including, without limitation, credit/debit card or PayPal payment information;
  * Shipping, billing and other information provided in connection with the purchase or shipment of JM Bullion products
  * Information about transactions with JM Bullion, such as purchase history
  * Any correspondence voluntarily submitted to the Website

JM Bullion may collect this personal information from you through various channels, including, but not limited to, through your voluntary submission of information to the Website, through requests initiated by you through the Website, through communication with third parties such as banks, through the collection and analysis of information concerning your computer and browsing activities, through the use of cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, Google Analytics, and through other sources permitted by law. In providing JM Bullion with your personal information, you consent to the transfer and storage of such information on our servers.

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. You agree that we may use your personal information to:

  * Collect and process payments and complete transactions
  * Provide the products, services and customer support you request
  * Resolve disputes
  * Troubleshoot problems
  * Prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities
  * Enforce our Terms and Conditions
  * Customize, measure and improve our services and content
  * Inform you about our products, services, updates and promotional offers

  2. **NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

The following are examples of the type of information that may be collected by JM Bullion from your web browser:

  * Details about your computer, device, application and network (including IP address, browser characteristics, device ID and characteristics, device operating system information and system language preferences)
  * Activities on our Website and usage patterns
  * Referring URLs, dates and times of Website visits, and clickstream data such as information commonly recorded in web server logs
  * Details about Internet or network usage (such as the URLs or domain names of websites you visit, information about applications that attempt to access your network, or traffic data)
  * Data about files and communications, such as potential malware or spam
  * Information stored in cookies, pixel tags, or web beacons
  * Analytic data from Google Analytics

**Cookies**

JM Bullion uses so-called “Cookies,” which are files that are stored on your computer that can be retrieved to assist in customizing your experience with our Website. A “Cookie” is a string of information that a Website stores on a user’s computer, and that the user’s browser provides to the Website each time the user submits a query to the Website. The purpose of a “Cookie” is to support the functionality of the Website, for example by keeping track of your visual preferences or controlling the frequency of “pop-up” windows, and identify the user as a unique user of the Website.

JM Bullion may use “Cookies” to customize your experience on the Website to your interests, to ensure that you do not repeatedly see content or informational messages that may be of no interest to you, and to store your password so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit the Website.  If you want to disable “Cookies”, there is a simple procedure in most Internet browsers that allows you to turn-off “Cookies.” Please remember, however, that “Cookies” may be required to allow you to use certain features of the Website.  JM Bullion ignores any and all Do Not Track requests and signals.

IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO HAVE “COOKIES” PLACED ON YOUR COMPUTER, YOU SHOULD ADJUST THE CORRESPONDING SETTING IN YOUR BROWSER TO REFUSE “COOKIES” BEFORE ACCESSING THE WEBSITE, WITH THE UNDERSTANDING THAT CERTAIN OF THE SERVICES AND CERTAIN FEATURES OF THE WEBSITE MAY NOT FUNCTION PROPERLY WITHOUT THE AID OF “COOKIES.” IF YOU REFUSE “COOKIES,” YOU ASSUME ALL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY RESULTING LOSS OF FUNCTIONALITY.

**Web Beacons/Web Bugs**

JM Bullion may utilize a software technology called “clear gifs” (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to “Cookies,” and are used to track the online movements of users. In contrast to “Cookies,” which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customer’s personal information. Rather, we may use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

From time to time, JM Bullion may release traffic data and information gathered using “Cookies” in the aggregate, such as by publishing a report on trends in the usage of the Website.

**Google Analytics**

JM Bullion use Google Analytics remarketing codes to log when users view specific pages or take specific actions on a website. This allows us to provide targeted advertising in the future. If you do not wish to receive this type of advertising from us in the future you can opt out using the DoubleClick opt-out page (http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) or the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page (<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>).

JM Bullion also utilizes Google Analytics Demographics and Interests Reporting.  Using the Ad Settings (<https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated>), you can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads.

  3. **SHARING OF PERSONAL/NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION**

JM Bullion may share your information where complying or in good faith attempting to comply with any law, regulation or law enforcement request; where JM Bullion has obtained your consent; where sharing or disclosure of your information is necessary between JM Bullion’s parents, subsidiaries, successors, assigns, licensees, affiliates, or business partners; where JM Bullion has been purchased by a third party; where sharing or disclosure of your information is necessary to respond to requests by government authorities; where your information is demanded by a court order or subpoena; where sharing or disclosure of your information is needed to protect the employees, independent contractors, officers, directors, members, users, or shareholders of JM Bullion; and where sharing or disclosure of your information is needed to help prevent against fraud or the violation of any applicable law, statute, regulation, ordinance, or treaty.  Without limiting the above, in an effort to respect your privacy, JM Bullion will maintain an email database, in-house, and will never sell your data or otherwise make it available for unaffiliated third party marketing purposes.

JM Bullion may also disclose personal information to those who help it provide products and services, including those who perform technical, administrative and data processing tasks, such as hosting, fulfillment, and data storage and security. These service providers are prohibited from using this personal information for any other purpose.

  4. **CONSENT TO RECEIVE EMAIL AND PROMOTIONAL MATERIALS**

By establishing an account, making a purchase or registering to receive the JM Bullion Newsletter, you consent to receive periodic commercial/promotional email communications from us. You may opt-out of receiving such promotional communications at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in each email, or by contacting our customer service department. By unsubscribing from our Promotional Newsletter only, you may still receive promotional materials and transactional emails from us in the future.

  5. **STORAGE AND SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Your personal information is stored and processed on computers and servers in the United States and, through your use of the Website, you unequivocally consent to the processing and storage of your personal information.

JM Bullion transmits information via the highest industry standard secure server (SSL) provided by Trustwave. This SSL creates the secure and encrypted https:// Website address for our important pages like Checkout and the My Account area. When you see the https:// website address, you know the information you are in-putting is protected and secure.

We comply with payment card industry data security standards that require merchants to implement security measures for credit card information. We never have access to your credit card information, as it is processed securely following the most stringent PCI-compliant standards. This ensures in the extremely unlikely case the JM Bullion servers are compromised, your financial details would not be accessible.

We have implemented and maintain generally accepted industry standards to protect against the unauthorized access, use, modification, destruction or disclosure of your personal information both during transmission and once we receive it. The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information during the registration process, we encrypt that information using state-of-the-art technology. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

JM Bullion assures you that we will use your personal information only for the purposes stated in the  **Terms of Use Agreement** and this Privacy Policy. We will not otherwise rent or sell your personal information to unaffiliated third parties, and we will prevent your email address from being recorded by “web crawlers” or “web spiders” to the best of our ability. If you believe that your email address has been recorded in this way, please let us know immediately.

The time periods for which we retain your personal information depend on the purposes for which we use it. JM Bullion will keep your personal information for as long as you are a registered user of our products and, thereafter, for no longer than is reasonably necessary for internal reporting and reconciliation purposes pursuant to legal requirements and to provide you with any feedback or information you might request or require.

If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can email us at [support@jmbullion.com](mailto:support@jmbullion.com).

  6. **LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

The JM Bullion Website may include links to other third party Websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of ours. If you submit personal information to a third party Website, your personal information will be solely governed by their privacy practices. JM Bullion encourages you to carefully read the privacy statement of any third party Website you visit.

  7. **ABILITY TO ACCESS, UPDATE AND CORRECT PERSONAL INFORMATION**

JM Bullion wants your personal information to be complete and accurate. By using the Website, you represent and warrant that all information you provide on any registration form or otherwise in connection with your use of the Website will be complete and accurate, and that you will update that information as necessary to maintain its completeness and accuracy. To confirm the completeness and accuracy of, or make changes to, your personal information, please contact us.

  8. **PURCHASE OR SALE OF THE WEBSITE, SOFTWARE, DATABASE, ASSOCIATED SERVICES, OR OTHER ASSETS:**

JM Bullion may purchase other businesses or sell components of its business, including, but not limited to, the Website and associated products and services.  In the event JM Bullion purchases another business or sells any component of its business, your personal and personally identifiable information will continue to be used consistent with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

  9. **UPDATES AND CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

JM Bullion may update this Privacy Policy at any time by posting additions or modifications on the Website. If at any point we decide to use personal information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by email or via a prominent notice on our Website, and where necessary we will seek the prior consent of our users.

  10. **REVOKING CONSENT/DELETING YOUR ACCOUNT**

You can delete or deactivate your JM Bullion account at any time by emailing support@jmbullion.com. When you delete your account, your personal information is removed from our database, unless we are required to save the data by applicable law, to prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations and/or enforce our Terms and Conditions.

You can access, review and change most of your personal information by logging in to the My Account area at JMBullion.com. You are required to promptly update your personal information if changes occur or information is inaccurate.

Your JM Bullion account and profile and the information contained therein are password protected. We assume no liability for the abuse of login data and passwords used.

JM Bullion treats data as a valuable asset that must be safeguarded and protected. As set forth above, we use reasonable security measures to protect your personal information against unauthorized access and disclosure.

  11. **CHILDREN’S ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION POLICY**

JM Bullion complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of the United States of America where it applies to our information protection activities. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen (13). If we learn that we have inadvertently collected personal information of a child under the age of thirteen (13) without proper consent, we will immediately delete that data from our database.

  12. **CALIFORNIA SHINE THE LIGHT LAW**

California residents have the right to receive information that identifies any third party companies or individuals that JM Bullion has shared your Personal Information with in the previous calendar year, as well as a description of the categories of Personal Information disclosed to that third party. You may obtain this information once a year and free of charge by contacting JM Bullion at the address below.

  13. **YOUR AGREEMENT TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

You expressly consent to JM Bullion’s processing of information as described in this Privacy Policy when you use or interact with the Website, provide information to us through our Website, purchase our products or assent to our  **Terms of Use Agreement**. In addition, when you use or interact with the Website, you specifically consent to our collection of personal information by automated means, such as cookies.

You may contact JM Bullion  directly if you have any questions regarding the content and material on the Website or if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy. Please contact our Compliance Officer at11700 Preston Road Ste 660153 Dallas, TX 75230 or e-mail [support@jmbullion.com](mailto:support@jmbullion.com).  . Additionally, you may contact your state or local consumer protection office or the Better Business Bureau.

© 2016 JM Bullion, Inc. All rights reserved.
